Tom Wallis

MSci Computing Science, Glasgow University

I'm a pragmatic worker who enjoys actively solving problems. Where many people from a strong academic background drift toward theoretical and heady approaches in a narrow field, I enjoy getting my hands dirty with practical work, drawing on an enthusiasm for fields in STEM, social sciences and humanities to attack interesting problems in genuinely new ways.

cv@tomwallis.net http://tomwallis.net/ Phone: 07704825401 Address: 1/2 29 Crathie Drive Glasgow G11 7XE

Research

I'm a first year computing science PhD candidate from Glasgow University, studying new methods for modelling contingent behaviour (especially in sociotechnical systems).

My research develops new ways to simluate variations in system behaviour when modelling, alongside my supervisor, Tim Storer. We are currently developing a series of libraries to do so, including ASP, an aspect-oriented programming (AOP) library encouraging separation of concerns in AOP, PyDySoFu, a library which exploits ASP's design to implement process fuzzing, and Fuzzi Moss, which employs process fuzzing to inject human-like faults into the behaviours of sociotechnical agents. A preliminary paper on the research is due to be published in the CAISE forum 2018.

http://github.com/probablytom/asp http://github.com/probablytom/ pydysofu http://github.com/twsswt/ fuzzi-moss

Education

Time	Institution	Qualification	Grade
2017 — 2021	Glasgow University	Ph.D Computing Science	Ongoing
2012 — 2017	Glasgow University	MSci Computing Science	B1 Average (2:1)
2006 — 2012	St. Mungos High School	N/A	AAB at Advanced Higher AAAABB at Higher

Employment

Time	Workplace	Job Title	Reference Contact
Jan 2018 — Present	Glasgow University	Demonstrator & Tutor	
May 2017 — Sep 2017	Obashi Tech	Software Engineer	pjw@obashitech.com
Sep 2016 — May 2017	Self-Employed	ERP & Python Consultat	nt
June 2016 — Sep 2016	Gardenia Tech	Software Engineer	contact@gardeniatech.com

These positions have variously tested my ability to learn adaptively, work strongly both in teams and on my own, and to take leading positions on large and important projects. Employers have found me to be an effective and flexible worker, but more importantly, a genuine asset to their teams in both individual and collaborative environments. To demonstrate: my main client as a self-employed consultant was my previous employer, Gardenia Technologies, and my subsequent employer, Obashi Technologies, now parially fund my postgraduate studies.